<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-05-21T20:47:34.857Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-05-21T20:47:34.857Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.7.2</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[拜登和文在寅会晤在即：朝核问题怎么办？]]></title>
        <id>https://cn.nytimes.com/asia-pacific/20210521/biden-north-korea-nuclear-weapons/dual</id>
        <link href="https://cn.nytimes.com/asia-pacific/20210521/biden-north-korea-nuclear-weapons/dual"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T10:36:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[DAVID E. SANGER, WILLIAM J. BROAD, CHOE SANG-HUN2021年5月21日1月，平壤举行的一场阅兵。过去四年，朝鲜的核武库和核燃料储备大约翻了一番。 Korean Central News Agency/Agence France-Presse, via Getty Images
WASHINGTON — Just weeks after President Biden took office, North Korea sent a subtle message to the new administration: It switched on key parts of its nuclear fuel production plant in Yongbyon, the aging complex where the country’s nuclear weapons program was born four decades ago.
华盛顿——就在拜登总统上任几周后，朝鲜向美国新政府发出了一个微妙的信息：它启动了宁边核燃料制造厂的关键部分，40年前，朝鲜的核武器计…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>纽约时报双语版</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[“小国机遇”：夹在中俄之间的蒙古为何不缺疫苗]]></title>
        <id>https://cn.nytimes.com/world/20210521/coronavirus-vaccine-mongolia/dual</id>
        <link href="https://cn.nytimes.com/world/20210521/coronavirus-vaccine-mongolia/dual"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T08:36:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[艾莎2021年5月21日在蒙古首都乌兰巴托的一所学校，一个新冠疫苗接种点。政府为每位接受完整疫苗接种的市民提供5万图格里克（约合113元人民币）。 Khasar Sandag for The New York Times
Mongolia, a country of grassy hills, vast deserts and endless skies, has a population not much bigger than Chicago’s. The small democratic nation is used to living in the shadow of its powerful neighbors, Russia and China.
蒙古，一个拥有草原山丘、广袤沙漠和无垠天空的国家，人口并不比芝加哥多多少。这个民主小国习惯于生活在其强大的邻国俄罗斯和中国的阴影下。
But during a pandemic, being a small nation sandwiched between two vaccine makers with global ambitions can hav…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>纽约时报双语版</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[胡椒喷雾、报警器和电击枪：亚裔美国人的新现实]]></title>
        <id>https://cn.nytimes.com/usa/20210521/asian-americans-attacks-nyc/dual</id>
        <link href="https://cn.nytimes.com/usa/20210521/asian-americans-attacks-nyc/dual"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T08:06:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[JESSICA CHIA2021年5月21日
Last spring Annie Chen, who works in human resources, read about an Asian woman who had been punched in the face and yelled at by a stranger just a few blocks from where she lived in Midtown Manhattan.
去年春天，供职于人力资源部门的安妮·陈（Annie Chen，音）读到一篇报道，说就在离她住的曼哈顿中城只有几个街区远的地方，一名亚裔女性被陌生人一拳打在脸上，还遭到言语辱骂。
Five days later, Ms. Chen, 25, bought her first canister of pepper spray.
五天后，25岁的安妮·陈第一次购买了胡椒喷雾。
She had been struck by the way the public perception of Asian-Americans had suddenly changed, she sa…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>纽约时报双语版</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[香港抗议：在街头被“消失”，在艺术中被重现]]></title>
        <id>https://cn.nytimes.com/china/20210521/hong-kong-protests-art/dual</id>
        <link href="https://cn.nytimes.com/china/20210521/hong-kong-protests-art/dual"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T06:36:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[MIKE IVES2021年5月21日艺术家萧伟恒。上个月，德国政府文化机构歌德学院的香港分院举办了他的一场混合媒体个人展《不合理行为》。 Lam Yik Fei for The New York Times
HONG KONG — As tear gas and fiery street clashes swirled around her two years ago, the Hong Kong painter Bouie Choi wondered how she would eventually render them on canvas.
香港——两年前，当催泪瓦斯和激烈的街头冲突萦绕在她身边，香港画家蔡钰娟思考自己最终会如何把它们展现在画布上。
The answer, exhibited at a local gallery about a year later, was “borrowed space_borrowed time,” her suite of brooding, ethereal landscapes that evoked ancient Chinese scroll pain…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>纽约时报双语版</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[“这一天迟早会来”：台湾新冠疫情大暴发]]></title>
        <id>https://cn.nytimes.com/asia-pacific/20210521/taiwan-covid-outbreak/dual</id>
        <link href="https://cn.nytimes.com/asia-pacific/20210521/taiwan-covid-outbreak/dual"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T02:36:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[RAYMOND ZHONG, AMY CHANG CHIEN2021年5月21日随着新冠病毒感染病例的突然增加，台湾政府已下令居民尽可能呆在家里，出门要戴口罩，但尚未宣布全面的行动限制。 Ritchie B Tongo/EPA, via Shutterstock
TAIPEI, Taiwan — Closed schools and restaurants offering takeout only. Lines around the block at testing sites. Politicians on television urging the public to stay calm.
台湾台北——学校停课，餐馆只供外卖。做病毒检测的人绕街区排起了长队。政客们在电视上敦促公众保持冷静。
If the scenes around Taiwan this week have a distinctly early pandemic feel, it is because the coronavirus is only now washing up on the island’s shores in for…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>纽约时报双语版</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[美国海关因新疆棉问题拦截一批优衣库衬衫]]></title>
        <id>https://cn.nytimes.com/business/20210521/uniqlo-forced-labor-china/dual</id>
        <link href="https://cn.nytimes.com/business/20210521/uniqlo-forced-labor-china/dual"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T02:36:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SAPNA MAHESHWARI2021年5月21日位于曼哈顿第五大道的优衣库商店。洛杉矶于1月拦截了一批来自优衣库的棉质服装。 Gabby Jones for The New York Times
United States customs officials blocked a shipment of men’s cotton shirts from the fast-fashion giant Uniqlo earlier this year because of concerns that the clothes had been produced in part by forced labor in the Xinjiang area of China.
今年早些时候，美国海关官员拦截了快时尚巨头优衣库(Uniqlo)的一批男士棉质衬衫，因为他们担心这些衣服部分是由中国新疆地区的强迫劳工生产的。
The issue attracted new attention this week when a ruling on Tuesday was posted on the U.S. Customs and…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>纽约时报双语版</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[一座被冻结在过去的北极圈苏联“鬼镇”]]></title>
        <id>https://cn.nytimes.com/travel/20210520/pyramiden-svalbard-mining-town/dual</id>
        <link href="https://cn.nytimes.com/travel/20210520/pyramiden-svalbard-mining-town/dual"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T10:06:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[JAMIE LAFFERTY2021年5月20日皮拉米登化工厂落满灰尘的入口通道。 Jamie Lafferty
Sergei Chernikov, my guide, had a bolt-action rifle slung over his shoulder — in case we came across any polar bears, he said, or in case they came across us.
我的导游谢尔盖·切尔尼科夫(Sergei Chernikov)肩膀上挂着一支栓动步枪，以防我们遇到北极熊，或者它遇到我们。
We were standing at the rudimentary dock in Pyramiden, a ghost town on the Norwegian archipelago of Svalbard, in the High Arctic. I’d heard that in 1998 the Russian government had tricked the town’s 1,000 residents into taking a holid…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>纽约时报双语版</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[印度新冠悲剧中，一对同生共死的双胞胎兄弟]]></title>
        <id>https://cn.nytimes.com/world/20210520/virus-india-twins-deaths/dual</id>
        <link href="https://cn.nytimes.com/world/20210520/virus-india-twins-deaths/dual"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T09:06:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[JEFFREY GETTLEMAN, SUHASINI RAJ2021年5月20日
NEW DELHI — Joefred and Ralfred Gregory moved through life as one.
新德里——乔弗雷德(Joefred)和拉尔弗雷德·格雷戈里(Ralfred Gregory)一生都像一个人一样度过。
They went to the same college. They studied the same thing. They wore matching clothes. They trimmed their beards the exact same way.
他们上的是同一所大学，学的是同样的东西。他们穿搭配的衣服。他们把胡子修剪得一模一样。
Identical twins, they were two handsome young men in northern India who above all else really loved each other. And when they both were struck by Covid-19 last month a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>纽约时报双语版</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[一百多年前，他用口罩帮助中国控制住一场瘟疫]]></title>
        <id>https://cn.nytimes.com/china/20210520/wu-lien-teh-china-masks/dual</id>
        <link href="https://cn.nytimes.com/china/20210520/wu-lien-teh-china-masks/dual"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T08:06:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[WUDAN YAN2021年5月20日 Library of Congress
In late 1910, a deadly plague started spreading in the northeast reaches of China, reaching the large city of Harbin. Tens of thousands of people coughed up blood; their skin pruned and turned purple. They all died.
1910年末，中国东北出现了一场致命的瘟疫，它蔓延到了大城市哈尔滨。数万人咳血，皮肤发青，变成紫色。最后他们都死了。
This outbreak sent the Qing government into a tailspin: They didn’t know what illness was causing these deaths, let alone how to control it. So they brought in one of the best trained doctors in As…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>纽约时报双语版</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[华裔少女被烧死悬案：FBI将以仇恨犯罪进行调查]]></title>
        <id>https://cn.nytimes.com/usa/20210520/maggie-long-murder-hate-crime/dual</id>
        <link href="https://cn.nytimes.com/usa/20210520/maggie-long-murder-hate-crime/dual"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T04:06:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NEIL VIGDOR2021年5月20日据帕克县警长办公室称，联邦调查局和科罗拉多州帕克县的警官们正在考虑玛姬·龙谋杀案可能是仇恨犯罪。 KDVR
For three and a half years, the killing of a Chinese-American teenager who was set on fire and burned alive in her family’s Colorado home has confounded investigators.
三年半前，一名华裔少女在科罗拉多的家中被人放火活活烧死。这起案件一直困扰着调查人员。
But now, as the federal government focuses on a spate of attacks targeting Asians, the 2017 killing of the teenager, Maggie Long, is being investigated as a hate crime, the local sheriff and one of Ms. Long’s sisters said in i…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>纽约时报双语版</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>